sadlier.com 2019-09-23

# Privacy Policy | Sadlier

William H. Sadlier, Inc. (“Sadlier”, “we” or “us”), the operator of this web site, is committed to preserving the privacy of those who visit our site (“Site”). This document will outline how we gather and utilize various sources of information obtained during your visit to the Site. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected at this Site. By using or accessing the Site, you signify your assent to our Privacy Policy.  **IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY YOU MAY NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE THE SITE.**

By using this Site, you represent and warrant that you are (i) located inside the U.S., or (ii) are located outside the EU or EEA and agree to be bound by U.S. laws. This Site is intended for users situated in the United States. We currently do not offer goods and services to the EU or EEA.

#### Personal Information and Non-Personal Information

When using the Site, in order to utilize some of the services, you may be asked to provide, or you may choose to upload, certain personally identifiable information about yourself ("Personal Information"). Personal Information can include your name, birth date/age, gender, email address, physical address, telephone number, billing and shipping information, position/title/subjects, school/parish, school grade, or other information you may provide. Similarly, when you post a photograph, enter or respond to a contest, survey, questionnaire, sweepstakes or other promotional feature, we may ask you for your name, address and email address or other personal information. We do not collect any Personal Information about you unless it is voluntarily provided by you. In addition, only people who are 13 or older may purchase products from our Site.

In addition, we may also collect non-personally identifiable information, such as IP host address, pages viewed, browser type, duration and frequency of visits, and other data, and may aggregate any information collected in a manner which does not identify any individual ("Aggregate Information"). Information obtained in connection with the Site may be intermingled with and used by us in conjunction with information obtained through sources other than the Site, including both offline and online sources.

#### Information Usage

We may use the Personal Information that we collect to help improve our Site, to process your orders/subscriptions/registrations, and to contact you about our products and services or those of our partners or other third parties from time to time.  **We do not sell your Personal Information to third parties or mass marketers**. For example, we will not sell another company your name or email address. Unless you consent to the disclosure of your Personal Information, only we and our affiliates, our technical consultants, third party auditors and other third parties who make our Site available, enhance its functionality, assist with the processing of your purchases, or provide associated services and/or who deal with you in delivering content, samples, products, gifts and prizes, have access to this information, and we require them to agree that they are covered by this policy.

Please note that Sadlier reserves the right to and may disclose Personal Information about you in response to (a) requests from local, state or federal law enforcement officials; (b) any judicial, administrative or similar proceeding or order, such as subpoena; (c) if required by law; or (d) to investigate suspected fraud, harassment, physical threats, or other violations of any law, rule or regulation, the Site rules or policies, or the rights of third parties or to investigate any suspected conduct which we deem improper. Please also note that we do reserve the right to transfer your personally identifiable information and other information to our successors in business and purchasers of Site assets.

#### Use of Cookies

Our Site may pass a "cookie" (a string of information that is sent by a web site to be resident on your system's hard drive, and/or temporarily in your computer's memory blocks). The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a particular page. The Site may use cookies in on-line catalogs to keep track of your status and contents of your shopping cart . or to retain information gathered in cookies to allow you access to password-protected areas of the Site . You may set your browser to decline cookies. If you do so, however, you may not be able to fully experience some interactive features of the Site.

#### Children's Online Privacy

This Site is not intended for persons under the age of 13, and we have no intention of collecting Personal Information from persons under the age of 13. Where appropriate, we take reasonable measures to inform children not to submit such information to our Site or in response to advertisements. If a child has provided us with personally identifiable information, we will use all reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

#### Links to Third Party Sites

Our Site may contain links to other web sites, including our affiliated or co-branded web sites. Other web sites may also reference or link to our Site. These "other" domains (web sites) are not controlled by Sadlier. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Site to read the privacy policies of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. We do not endorse, screen or approve, and are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other web sites. Visiting these other web sites is at your own risk.

#### Security

Sadlier will not be liable for disclosures of your Personal Information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties. We have undertaken all commercially reasonable efforts to prevent unauthorized Internet access to visitor data retained in our servers, however, due to the inherent open nature of the Internet, Sadlier cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or any information provided online, and you do so at your own risk. Users must accept all risks associated with any data transmission, including the risk that their personal information may be intercepted in transit.

#### Customer Review and Chat Areas

You should be aware that Personal Information which you voluntarily include and transmit online may be viewed and used by others. Users of the Site are solely responsible for the content of messages they post online including on public forums. These forums include but are not limited to on and offsite customer review areas, chat rooms, bulletin boards, blogs or other publicly accessible forums which may be viewed and used by anyone with access to such forums. Users should be aware that when they voluntarily disclose Personal Information within a public forum that user information may be collected and used by others. The Site is unable to control such uses of your Personal Information, and by using such services you assume the risk that the Personal Information provided by you may be viewed and used by third parties.

#### Policy Modifications/Opt-Out

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this policy at any time. However, if at any time in the future we plan to use Personal Information in a way that differs from this policy, we will post such changes here. Your continued use of the Service following the posting of any changes to this policy means you accept such changes. Please check this page periodically for changes to this Privacy Policy.

We give you the option to remove your Personal Information from our list of active users completely. All unsubscribe, opt-out, or account deletion requests should be sent to us at webmaster@sadlier.com and we will process your request within a reasonable time after receipt. We are not responsible for removing your Personal Information from the lists of any third party who has previously been provided your information in accordance with this policy.

#### Communications with Sadlier

By providing your email address to us, you expressly consent to receive emails from us. We may use email to communicate with you, to send information that you have requested or to send information about other products or services developed or provided by us, provided that, we will not give your email address to another party to promote their products or services directly to you.

Any communication or material you transmit to us by email or otherwise, including any data, questions, comments, suggestions, or the like is, and will be treated as, non-confidential and nonproprietary. Except to the extent expressly covered by this policy, anything you transmit or post may be used by us for any purpose, including but not limited to, reproduction, disclosure, transmission, publication, broadcast and posting. Furthermore, you expressly agree that we are free to use any ideas, concepts, know-how, or techniques contained in any communication you send to us without compensation and for any purpose whatsoever, including but not limited to, developing, manufacturing and marketing products and services using such information.

#### Site Terms and Conditions

Use of this Site is governed by, and subject to, the legal notices contained at [Terms and Conditions](http://schoolstore.sadlier.com/termsandconditions.aspx). Your use, or access, of the Site constitutes your agreement to be bound by these provisions.  **IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THESE TERMS AND CONDITIONS YOU MAY NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE THE SITE.**

#### Contact

If you have any questions about Sadlier's Privacy Policy you can contact:

Webmaster  
William H. Sadlier, Inc.  
9 Pine Street  
New York, NY 10005  
212-227-2120  
Fax: 212-267-8696  
webmaster@sadlier.com

#### United States of America

Our Site is maintained in the United States of America. By using the Site, you authorize the export of Personal Information to the USA and its storage and use as specified in this policy.

**Effective Date:**  This Privacy Policy is effective and was last updated on May 25, 2018.
